Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Labor and Radicalism Photograph Collection PHOTOS.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Labor and Radicalism Photograph Collection
1860-1985
1940-1965
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
McLaughlin, Brian M.
Pollet, Miriam
Smith, Jessica, 1895-1983
Vladeck, Stephen C.
PHOTOS.001
10.5 Linear Feet in 12 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize flat boxes, 14 folders in three flat-file drawers.
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Labor and Radicalism Photograph Collection is an assemblage of photographs collected by or separated from manuscript collections or organizational records in the library's holdings. Materials include original photographs, reproductions from books, pamphlets, periodicals, and photoreproductions of engravings, drawings, and cartoons concerning radicalism and the trade union movement in Europe and the United States.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Accurals Note
Images continue to be added to the collection from various sources, including the Library's archival and manuscript collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was created by Tamiment Library through several donations over the years including Brian M. McLaughlin in 1997, Miriam Pollet in 2008, Jessica Smith in 1997, and Stephen C. Vladeck in 1978; additonal materials were found in the repository. The accession numbers associated with this collection are NPA.2005.009, 2018.062, 2018.063, 2019.023, NAP.1993.018, 2018.064, NPA.2004.001, NPA.2003.035, NPA.2003.034, NPA.2003.020, NPA.2000.279, NPA.2000.313, NPA.2000.315, NPA.2000.324, NPA.2000.251, NPA.2000.252, 1950.197, 2013.021, 2014.111, 1963.014, 2011.068, NPA.2005.011, NPA.2004.066, NPA.2004.065, and NPA.2004.071.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject in the finding aid; within the collection they are arranged numerically.
Historical/Biographical Note
This is an expanding artificial collection originally known as the Tamiment Library / Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives General Photograph Collection. Apart from the material transferred to the Library's vertical files, the collection holds photographic images that complement, but are not part of or do not fit into the scope of the Library's other holdings.
Custodial History note
Unlike other Tamiment/Wagner photograph collections, these images do not come from just one individual or organizational donor, but from myriad different sources, and have been merged to form an artificial collection. It was created (and is still being added to) to serve as a "home" for useful images that do not fit into the scope of Tamiment's regular archival collections. Other images are drawn from many different sources. These include photograph, book illustrations, and other published materials that have been separated from Tamiment/Wagner papers and manuscript collections because they are not related to the specific subjects of the collections, but are nonetheless relevant to Tamiment/Wagner subject areas.
Scope and Content Note
The materials in this collection include original photographs, reproductions from books, pamphlets, periodicals, and photoreproductions of engravings, drawings, and cartoons concerning radicalism and the trade union movement in Europe and the United States. The vast majority of the images are portraits of individuals including Eugene Debs, Morris Hillquit, Rose Schneiderman, Karl Kautsky, Algernon Lee, James Hudson Maurer, Rose Pastor Stokes and Norman Thomas. The remainder of the collection includes a wide (if sometimes idiosyncratic) variety of images, including strikes, demonstrations, Socialist Party, and other radical left organizations' events and celebrations, workers' summer resorts, women and minority workers, and sweatshops.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements Note
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use photocopies of the Triangle Fire photographs (Folder 487).
Radicals |v Portraits.; Pamphlets.; Strikes and lockouts -- United States -- Pictorial works.; Socialists |v Portraits.; Working class |z United States |v Pictorial works.; Anarchists |v Portraits.; Clippings (information artifacts); Black-and-white photographs.; Labor movement -- United States -- Pictorial works.; Communists |v Portraits.; De Leon, Solon, 1883-; Laidler, Harry W. (Harry Wellington), 1884-1970; Zaritsky, Max, 1885-1959; Schneiderman, Rose, 1882-1972 -- Portraits.; Shiplacoff, A. I. (Abraham Isaac), 1877-1936 -- Portraits.; Solomon, Charles; Stokes, Rose Pastor, 1879-1933 -- Portraits.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968 -- Portraits.; Vladeck, B. (Baruch), 1886-1938; Panken, Jacob, 1879-1968 -- Portraits; Oneal, James, 1875-1962 -- Portraits.; Maurer, James H. (James Hudson), 1864- -- Portraits.; Mailly, Bertha -- Portraits.; London, Meyer, 1871-1926 -- Portraits; Lee, Algernon; Kautsky, Karl, 1854-1938; Josephson, Ben, 1895-1980; Hillquit, Morris, 1869-1933 -- Portraits.; Halushka, Mendel V., 1904-1958 -- Portraits.; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Gellert, Hugo, 1892-1985; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926 -- Portraits.; Cowl, Carl; Cacchione, Peter V., 1897-1947; Colby, Josephine -- Portraits; Beffel, John Nicholas; McLaughlin, Brian M.; Pollet, Miriam; Smith, Jessica, 1895-1983; Vladeck, Stephen C.
- Abbott, Berenice; Atget, Eugène, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Abbott, Leonard (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Actor's Equity (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AFL (Scranton, PA) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO (Box 1, Folder 5)
- AFL-CIO Washington Unemployment Conference (Box 1, Folder 6)
- African-Americans and Labor Unions (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Aleinikoff, Nicholas (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Allen, Devere (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Allen, Woody (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union (Flat-file-folder 3, Tray 2)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers Union (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Amalgamated Housing Corp. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- American Committee for Protection of Foreign born (Box 1, Folder 13)
- American Labor Party (Box 1, Folder 14, Box Shared Tamiment 048, Folder 10)
- American Labor Party - New York State (Box 1, Folder 15)
- American League Against War and Fascism (Box 1, Folder 16)
- American Writers Conference (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Ameringer, Oscar (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Anarchists (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Anthony, Susan B. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Anti War March (?), NYC (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Anti-Communism (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Anti-Semitism (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Anti-war - pamphlet-"War - What For?" by George Kirkpatrick, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Avksentieff (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Axelrod, Paul (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Baker, Robert E. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Bakounine, Michele (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Balabanoff, Angelica (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Baldwin, Roger N. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Baner, Otto (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Bax, E. Belfort (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Beardsley, Samuel E. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Bebel, August (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Becker, Maurice (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Beckerman, Abraham (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Beffel, John (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Benson, Allan L. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Berger, Meta L. (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Berger, Victor L. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Berkman, Alexander (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Bernard, John T. (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Bessant, Annie (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Bernhardt, Debra (Box 1, Folder 42.1)
- Betain (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Block, Anita C. (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Block, Julius (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Bloor, (Mother) Ella Reeve (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Blum, Leon (Prime Minister of France) (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Blum, S. (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Bohn, William (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Branstettor, Otto (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Breshkovsky, Katherine (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Brewer, George D. (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Brewery Workers (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Bridges, Harry (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Brooklyn (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Brooklyn Labor Lyceum (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Brookwood Labor College (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Broun, Heywood (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Browder, Earl (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Brown, John (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Bryan, William Jennings (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Bryant, Louise (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Buhle, Paul (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Building and Construction Trades Council, Dec 15 1991 (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 2)
- Burnham, Louis (Box 12, Folder 552)
- Cacchione, Peter V. (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Cahan, Abraham (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Callery, Ida Hayman (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Caln, Abe (Mrs.) (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Camp Nitgedaiget (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Camp Saskatchewan, ca. 1960-1965 (Box Shared Tamiment XOS001)
- Camp Tamiment (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 4)
- Camp Tamiment (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Camp Unity (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Cannon, James P. (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Canton Church Bombing (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Carey, James F. (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Carpenter, Edward (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Cartoons and Caricatures (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Cartoons - Comic Book (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Cartoons - Drawings (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Cartoons - Labor (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Cartoons - US-pre-1960 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Cassidy, Edward F. (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Cemeteries - Pere Lachaise Cemetery (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Chase, John C. (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Child Labor (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Chinatown - New York City (Box 2, Folder 85)
- Chinese Labor - San Francisco (Box 2, Folder 86)
- CIO - Leadership and Miscellaneous (Flat-file-folder 1, Tray 3, Flat-file-folder 8, Tray 3)
- CIO - Leadership and Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 87)
- Citrine, Sir Walter (Box 2, Folder 88)
- Clarke, Stanley J. (Box 2, Folder 89)
- Clevite Harris Products Co, OH (Box 2, Folder 90)
- Coal mines and Mining (Box 2, Folder 91)
- Coal mines and Mining (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 1)
- Colby, Josephine (Box 2, Folder 92)
- Communism - WWII (Box 3, Folder 93)
- Communist Party (Box 3, Folder 94)
- Communist Party - NY Estonian Workers Club (Box 3, Folder 95)
- Communist Party - Young Workers League (Box 3, Folder 96)
- Cement and Concrete Workers Union, 1993 (Box Shared Tamiment XOS002, Folder 1)
- Connolly, James (Box 3, Folder 97)
- Conscientious Objectors Prison Camps, WWI (Box 3, Folder 98)
- Convict Labor (Box 3, Folder 99)
- Conway, Moncure D. (Box 3, Folder 100)
- Coolidge, Albert Sprague (Box 3, Folder 101)
- Corbett, Ray (Box 3, Folder 102)
- CORE - Congress of Racial Equality (Box 3, Folder 103)
- Cosmonauts, USSR (Box 3, Folder 104)
- Coughlin, Father Charles (Box 3, Folder 105)
- Counts George S. (Box 3, Folder 106)
- Cowl, Carl (Box 3, Folder 107)
- Coxey's Army (Box 3, Folder 108)
- Crocker, Richard (Box 3, Folder 109)
- Crossworth, Frank (Box 3, Folder 110)
- Crowe, Kenneth (Box 12, Folder 553)
- Cuba (Box 3, Folder 111)
- Dahme, Evelyn (Box 3, Folder 112)
- Daniels, Franz (Box 3, Folder 113)
- Davis, Benjamin J. Jr. (Box 3, Folder 114)
- Davis, G.W. ("PAP") (Box 3, Folder 115)
- De Leon, Solon (Box 3, Folder 116)
- de Man, Henry (Box 3, Folder 117)
- Debs, E.V. (Box Shared Tamiment OS003, Folder 2)
- Debs, E.V. (Box 3, Folder 118)
- Debs, E.V. (Box Shared Tamiment XOS003, Folder 1)
- Deleon, Daniel (Box 3, Folder 119)
- Desser, A. A. (Box 3, Folder 120)
- Deutsch, Julius (Box 3, Folder 121)
- Dewey, John (Box 3, Folder 122)
- Diana, Raymond (Box 3, Folder 123)
- Dietzgen, Eugene (Box 3, Folder 124)
- Donnely, Igantius (Box 3, Folder 125)
- Douglas, Frederick (Box 3, Folder 126)
- Dreier, Mary E. (Women's Trade Union League) (Box 3, Folder 127)
- Du Bois, W.E.B. (Box 3, Folder 128)
- Du Bois, W.E.B. (Box Shared Tamiment OS003, Folder 3)
- Dubinsky, David (ILGWU) (Box 3, Folder 129)
- Durant, Will and Auriel (Box 3, Folder 130)
- Durruti, Buenaventura (Box 3, Folder 131)
- Eastman, Max (Box 3, Folder 132)
- Eight Hour Law (Box 3, Folder 133)
- Einstein, Albert (Box 3, Folder 134)
- Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box 3, Folder 135)
- Eleanor Roosevelt Memorial Foundation (Box 3, Folder 554)
- Ellis Island (Box 3, Folder 136)
- Ellis, Havelock (Box 3, Folder 137)
- Ely, Richard T. (Box 3, Folder 138)
- Employment - Non-Traditional (Box Shared Tamiment OS003, Folder 4)
- Employment - Non-Traditional (Box 3, Folder 139)
- Engels, Friedrich (Box 3, Folder 140)
- Equi, Dr. Marie (Box 3, Folder 141)
- Erlich, Henryck (Box 3, Folder 142)
- Farms and Farming (Box 3, Folder 143)
- Fasanella, Ralph (Box 3, Folder 144)
- Federacion Libre of Puerto Rico (September 1900) (Box 3, Folder 579)
- Field, Frederick V. (Box 3, Folder 145)
- Finnish Workers Hall (NYC) (Box 3, Folder 146)
- Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley (Box 3, Folder 147)
- Ford, Robert (Box 3, Folder 148)
- Forge, Maurice (Box 3, Folder 148.1)
- Foster, William S. (Box 3, Folder 149)
- Friedman, Esther (Box 3, Folder 150)
- Fur and Leather Workers (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 5)
- Fur and Leather Workers (Box 3, Folder 151)
- Fur and Leather Workers (Flat-file-folder 3, Tray 2)
- Furriers Joint Council, undated; October 28, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 152)
- Furriers Joint Council (Box Shared Tamiment OS005, Folder 5)
- Gates, John (Box 3, Folder 153)
- Gavin, D. J. ("Jimi") (Box 3, Folder 154)
- Gellert, Hugo (Box 3, Folder 155)
- George, Henry (Box 4, Folder 156)
- Gerber, Julius (Box 4, Folder 157)
- Gilman, Charlotte Perkins (Box 4, Folder 158)
- Goetz, Bernhard (Box 4, Folder 159)
- Gold, Ben (Box 4, Folder 160)
- Goldfogle, Henry M. (Box 4, Folder 161)
- Goldman, Emma (Box 4, Folder 162)
- Goldman, Emma (Box Shared Tamiment OS003, Folder 1)
- Goldmark, Josephine (Box 4, Folder 163)
- Goldmark, Pauline (Box 4, Folder 164)
- Gompers, Samuel (Box Shared Tamiment XOS002, Folder 1)
- Gompers, Samuel (Box 4, Folder 165)
- Gordin, Jacob (Box 4, Folder 166)
- Gordon, F.G.R. (Box 4, Folder 167)
- Gorki, Maxime (Box 4, Folder 168)
- Gorman, Pat (Box 4, Folder 169)
- Government and Civic Employees, AFL-CIO (Box 4, Folder 170)
- Gray, Laura (Box 4, Folder 171)
- Greenwich House (Box 4, Folder 172)
- Guesde, Jules (Box 4, Folder 173)
- Haggerty, Thomas H. (Box 4, Folder 174)
- Halushka, Mendel V. (Box 4, Folder 175)
- Hanford, Benjamin (Box 4, Folder 176)
- Hapgood, Powers (Box 4, Folder 177)
- Hardie, Keir (Box 4, Folder 178)
- Harper, Ida Husted (Box 4, Folder 179)
- Harriman, Job (Box 4, Folder 180)
- Hartford (Conn.) Labor Council (Box 4, Folder 181)
- Hatters (United) (Box 4, Folder 182)
- Hayman, Sandy (Box 4, Folder 183)
- Haymarket Square Riot, Chicago (Box 4, Folder 184)
- Haywood, William D.C. (Box 4, Folder 185)
- Held, Adolph (Box 4, Folder 186)
- Herndon, Angelo (Box 4, Folder 187)
- Herriot (Box 4, Folder 188)
- Hertzl, Theodore (Box 4, Folder 189)
- Highlander School (Box 4, Folder 190)
- Hillman, Sidney (Box 4, Folder 191)
- Hillquit, Morris (Box 4, Folder 192)
- Hillstrom, Joseph (Joe Hill) (Box 4, Folder 193)
- Hine, Lewis (misc. photos), 1905-1934 (Box 4, Folder 194, Box 14, Folder 5)
- Hoan, Daniel W. (Box 4, Folder 195)
- Homelessness (Box 4, Folder 196)
- Hook, Sidney (Box 4, Folder 197)
- Hotel Victoria, ca. 1930-1940 (Box Shared Tamiment XOS001)
- Hughan, Jessie Wallace (Box 4, Folder 198)
- Hughes, John (Box 4, Folder 199)
- Hurovick, Dr.(?) (Box 4, Folder 200)
- Huysman, Dr. Cam. (Box 4, Folder 201)
- Hyman, Joseph C. (Box 4, Folder 202)
- Hyndman, H.M. (Box 4, Folder 203)
- I.W.W. (Box 4, Folder 204)
- Ibarruri, Dolores (Box 4, Folder 205)
- Idar, Jovita (Box 4, Folder 206)
- ILGWU (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 1)
- ILGWU (Box 4, Folder 207)
- ILGWU (Reference copies from ILGWU Archives at Cornell University) (Box 4, Folder 208)
- Immigrants (Box 4, Folder 209)
- Inglis, Agnes (Box 4, Folder 210)
- International Association of Machinists (I.A.M.) (Box 4, Folder 211)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (Box 12, Folder 580)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters (Box 4, Folder 212)
- International Brotherhood of Teamsters (Box Shared Tamiment XOS003, Folder 1)
- International Longshoremen's Association (Box 5, Folder 213)
- International School of Social Economy, Girard Training School (Box 5, Folder 214)
- International Socialist Convention (Box 5, Folder 215)
- International Trade Union Conference (Box 5, Folder 216)
- International Workers Order (Box 5, Folder 217)
- Industrial Workers of the World, 1912 (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 4)
- Iolle, Dorothee (Box 5, Folder 218)
- Ipatiev, U. (Box 5, Folder 219)
- Italian-American Labor Council (Box 5, Folder 220)
- Jaures, Jean (Box 5, Folder 221)
- Jewish Labor Bund (Box 12, Folder 555)
- Jewish Labor Committee (Box 5, Folder 222)
- Jewish Labor Committee (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 1)
- Jewish Radicals (Box Shared Tamiment XOS003, Folder 1)
- Jewish Theater (Box 5, Folder 223)
- Jewish Workers (Box 5, Folder 224)
- John Reed Clubs (Box 5, Folder 225)
- Jonas, Alexander (Box 5, Folder 226)
- Jones, "Mother" Mary (Box 5, Folder 227)
- Josephson, Ben (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 1)
- Josephson, Ben (Box 5, Folder 228)
- Jouhaux, Leon (Box 5, Folder 229)
- Karlin, William (Box 5, Folder 230)
- Karolyi, (Count) Michael (Box 5, Folder 231)
- Karsner, David (Box 5, Folder 232)
- Katayama, Sen Jo (Box 5, Folder 233)
- Katz, Rudolph (Box 5, Folder 234)
- Kautsky, Karl (Box 5, Folder 235)
- Keinard, Benjamin Franklin (Box 5, Folder 236)
- Kelley, Florence (Box 5, Folder 237)
- Kennedy, Edward (Box 5, Folder 581)
- King, Jr., Martin Luther (Box 5, Folder 238)
- Kirkpatrick, George R. (Box 5, Folder 239)
- Knights of Labor (Box 5, Folder 240)
- Konvitz, Dr. Milton R. (Box 5, Folder 241)
- Korean War (Box 5, Folder 242)
- Kort, Neil, retirement dinner, 1966 (Box Shared Tamiment 016, Folder 4)
- Kraus, Dorothy and Henry (Box 5, Folder 243)
- Krebs, Richard (Box 5, Folder 244)
- Kropotkin, Peter (Box 5, Folder 245)
- Krueger, M.C. (Box 5, Folder 246)
- Krzycki, Leo (Box 5, Folder 247)
- Kuhn, Henry (Box 5, Folder 248)
- La Salle, Ferdinand (Box 5, Folder 249)
- Labor and Laboring Classes (Box 5, Folder 250)
- Labor Day (Box 5, Folder 251)
- Labor Film Service (Box 12, Folder 556)
- Labor for Peace (Box 5, Folder 252)
- Labor Solidarity (Rally, West Virginia), 1989 (Flat-file-folder 3, Tray 2)
- Laidler, Harry (Box 5, Folder 253)
- Lajpat Rai, Lala (Box 5, Folder 254)
- Landis, Kenneshaw Mountain (Box 5, Folder 255)
- Larkin, James (Box 5, Folder 256)
- Laski, Harold J. (Box 5, Folder 257)
- Lazarus, Emma (Box 5, Folder 258)
- Lee Family (Box 5, Folder 259)
- Lee, Algernon (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 2)
- Lee, Algernon (Box 5, Folder 260)
- Lehman, Herbert (Box 5, Folder 261)
- Lemlich, Clara (Box 5, Folder 262)
- Lenin, Vladimir Ilyich (Box 5, Folder 263)
- Leon Trotsky House Museum, Mexico City (Box 5, Folder 557)
- Levitas, Solomon M. (Box 5, Folder 264)
- Lewis, John C. (Box 5, Folder 265)
- Lewis, Lena Morrow (Box 5, Folder 266)
- Liebknecht, Karl (Box 5, Folder 267)
- Liebknecht, Wilhelm (Box 5, Folder 268)
- Lillienthal, Meta Stern (Box 5, Folder 269)
- Lipsky, Louis (Box 5, Folder 270)
- London, Jack (Box 5, Folder 271)
- London, Meyer (Box 5, Folder 272)
- London, Meyer (Box Shared Tamiment XOS003, Folder 1)
- Longuet, Jean (Box 5, Folder 273)
- Lorwin, Lewis (Box 6, Folder 274)
- Low, Bela (Box 6, Folder 275)
- Lowenfels, Walter (Box 12, Folder 558)
- Luhan, Mabel (Ganson) Dodge (Box 6, Folder 276)
- Lum, Dyer D. (Box 6, Folder 277)
- Lunacharsky, a (Box 6, Folder 278)
- Luxemberg, Rosa (Box 6, Folder 279)
- Lynching (Box 12, Folder 559)
- MacDonald, J. Ramsay (Box 6, Folder 280)
- Mailly, Bertha Howell (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 2)
- Mailly, Bertha Howell (Box 6, Folder 281)
- Mailly, William (Box 6, Folder 281.1)
- Maley, Anna (Box 6, Folder 282)
- Malkiel, Theresa (Box 6, Folder 283)
- Manson, Julius (Box 6, Folder 284)
- Mao, Tse-Tung (Box 6, Folder 285)
- Marcantonio, Vito (Box 6, Folder 286)
- March on Washington (Box 6, Folder 287)
- March on Washington Movement (Box 6, Folder 288)
- Marine Engineers Beneficial Association (Box 6, Folder 289)
- Markoff, Abraham (Box 6, Folder 290)
- Marshall, Ray (Box 6, Folder 290.1)
- Martin, Alberto (A/K/A Frank R. Lopez) (Box 6, Folder 291)
- Martin, Homer (Box 6, Folder 292)
- Marx, Karl (Box 6, Folder 293)
- Masses, The (Box 6, Folder 294)
- Matchett, Charles (Box 6, Folder 295)
- Matteotti, Giacomo (Box 6, Folder 296)
- Maurer, James Hudson (Box 6, Folder 297)
- May Day (Box 6, Folder 298)
- McCarthy, Joseph (Box 6, Folder 299)
- McCartney, Rev. Frederic O. (Box 6, Folder 300)
- McDonald, Grace (Box 6, Folder 301)
- Meany, George (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 1)
- Meany, George (Box 6, Folder 302)
- Medem, Bladumip (Box 6, Folder 303)
- Mencken, Henry L. (Box 6, Folder 304)
- Mertens (Box 6, Folder 305)
- Michel, Louise (Box 6, Folder 306)
- Miliukov, Paul (Box 6, Folder 307)
- Mine Disaster - Cherry, Illinois (Box 6, Folder 308)
- Mishnun, Eleanor (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 1)
- Mishnun, Eleanor (Box 6, Folder 309)
- Mooney, Thomas Joseph (Box 6, Folder 310, Box 19)
- Morris, William (Box 6, Folder 311)
- Moscow Subway (Box 6, Folder 312)
- Murals (Box 6, Folder 313)
- Murphy, J.P. (Box 6, Folder 314)
- Murray, Philip (Box 12, Folder 582)
- Muste, A.J. (Box 6, Folder 315)
- NAACP Legal Defense Fund (Box 6, Folder 316)
- Nathan, Maud (Box 6, Folder 317)
- National Agricultural Workers Unions (Box 6, Folder 318)
- National Executive Board of the Congress of Industrial Organizations, June 14, 1939 (Box Shared Tamiment 081, Folder 5)
- National Maritime Union (Box 6, Folder 319)
- National Maritime Union (Flat-file 7, Drawer 14)
- National Negro Congress (Box 6, Folder 320, Flat-file-folder 3, Tray 3)
- Naughton, Norma F. [CWA Local 1150] (Box 6, Folder 321)
- New Jersey Industrial Council, Sep 10, 1943 (Box Shared Tamiment OS005, Folder 5)
- New Leader (Box Shared Tamiment OS003, Folder 7)
- New Leader (Box 6, Folder 322)
- New Workers School (Box Shared Tamiment OS003, Folder 8)
- New Workers School (Box 7, Folder 323)
- New York City Council/City Hall Reporters Annual Outing, Jun 28, 1971 (Flat-file-folder 5, Tray 1)
- New York City Lower Eastside (Box 7, Folder 323.1)
- New York Typographical Union No.6 (Box 7, Folder 324)
- Newspaper Guild [there is nothing in this folder but a cross reference to NP1 Negative file- Brown, Heywood.] (Box 7, Folder 322.1)
- NLRB (cartoons) (Box 7, Folder 325)
- No Conscription League of New York (Box 7, Folder 326)
- Norden, Albert (Box 7, Folder 327)
- O'Hare, Frank and Kate Richards (Box 7, Folder 328)
- O'Reilly, Leonora (Box 7, Folder 329)
- Oates, Joe (I.W.W.) (Box 7, Folder 330)
- Oneal, James (Box 7, Folder 331)
- Owen, Robert (Box 7, Folder 332)
- Padmore, George (Box 12, Folder 560)
- Panken, Jacob (Box 7, Folder 333)
- Paper Box Makers Union (Box 7, Folder 334)
- Peekskill Riots and Concert (Box Shared Tamiment OS003, Folder 5)
- Peekskill Riots and Concert (Box 7, Folder 335)
- Peng Shu-Tse (Box 7, Folder 336)
- Perkins, Frances (Box 7, Folder 337)
- Perlman, Selig (Box 7, Folder 338)
- Pesota, Rose (Box 7, Folder 339)
- Phillips, Wendell (Box 7, Folder 340)
- Pickens, William (NAACP) (Box 7, Folder 341)
- Piecework (Box 7, Folder 342)
- Plekhanov, Georgii Valentinovich (Box 7, Folder 343)
- Podmaka, Rose (Box 7, Folder 344)
- Porter, Edna (Box 7, Folder 345)
- Porter, Winfield P. (Box 7, Folder 346)
- Posters and Broadsides (from the Tamiment/Wagner Collection)-Reference Prints (Box 7, Folder 347)
- Potofsky, Jacob (Box 7, Folder 348)
- Powderly, Terence Vincent (Box 7, Folder 349)
- Prevey, Margaret (Box 7, Folder 350)
- Prisons-Kansas State Penitentiary (Box 7, Folder 351)
- Progressive Party (Flat-file-folder 3, Tray 2)
- Progressive Party (Flat-file-folder 2)
- Progressive Party (Box Shared Tamiment OS006, Folder 4)
- Progressive Party (Box 12, Folder 561)
- Quill, Michael J. (Box 7, Folder 352)
- Quill, Molly (Box 7, Folder 352.1)
- Quinn, Charles F.(Pa. Fed. of Labor) (Box 7, Folder 353)
- Rabinowitz (Shalom Aleichem) (Box 7, Folder 354)
- Rand School - Folder 1: Auditorium (Box 7, Folder 355)